<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DATA@RENSSELAER on Data@Rensselaer</title>
    <link>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DATA@RENSSELAER on Data@Rensselaer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Notebooks</title>
      <link>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/modules/how-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/modules/how-to/</guid>
      <description>Starting Up Jupyter Notebook To use the Jupyter notebook, you have to run the following command (in either Terminal for Mac or Command Prompt for Windows) to see the application in your web broswer:
jupyter notebook  You can also launch it through the Anaconda Navigator startup page.
Once open you will be greeted with the dashboard:
 The &amp;ldquo;Files&amp;rdquo; tab is where all of your files are kept, The &amp;ldquo;Running&amp;rdquo; tab keeps track of all the processes and notebooks currently live, and The &amp;ldquo;Clusters&amp;rdquo; tab is provided by IPython Parallel, Python&amp;rsquo;s parallel computing framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyTorch</title>
      <link>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/modules/pytorch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/modules/pytorch/</guid>
      <description>Pytorch with the MNIST Dataset - MINST rpi.analyticsdojo.com
   From Kaggle: &#34;MNIST (&#34;Modified National Institute of Standards and Technology&#34;) is the de facto “hello world” dataset of computer vision. Since its release in 1999, this classic dataset of handwritten images has served as the basis for benchmarking classification algorithms. As new machine learning techniques emerge, MNIST remains a reliable resource for researchers and learners alike.&#34;
Read more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Regression</title>
      <link>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/modules/linearregression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/modules/linearregression/</guid>
      <description>This project will work on how to predict the prices of homes based on the properties of the house. I will determine which house affected the final sale price and how effectively we can predict the sale price.Here&#39;s a brief description of the columns in the data:
   Learning ObjectivesBy the end of this notebook, the reader should be able to perform Linear Regression techniques in python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principle Component Analysis</title>
      <link>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/modules/pca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/modules/pca/</guid>
      <description>Sections: PCA (Principal Component Analysis)) Origin Learning Objective PCA  Eigenvectors Running PCA Homework     Origin This notebook was adapted from amueller&#39;s notebook, &#34;1 - PCA&#34;. Here is the link to his repository https://github.com/amueller/tutorial_ml_gkbionics.git .
This notebook provides examples for eigenvalues and eigenvectors in LaTeX and python.
   Learning Objective  How the Principal Componenet Analysis (PCA) works. How PCA can be used to do dimensionality reduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis</title>
      <link>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/modules/time_series_basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/modules/time_series_basic/</guid>
      <description>Time Series Analysis         Time Series Analysis A time series is a series of data points indexed (or listed or graphed) in time order. Time series analysis pertains to methods extracting meaningful statistics from time series data. This is commonly used for forecasting and other models.
   Learning Objectives  Understand the uses of Time Series Analysis Understand the pros and cons of various TSA methods, including differentiating between linear and non-linear methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/_footer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/_footer/</guid>
      <description>DATA@RENSSELAER was funded by the teaching and learning collaboratory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rpi-data.analyticsdojo.com/_header/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>